In this video, I'd like you
在这段视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to work in through our example
我想通过例子来向大家展示
to show how a neural
一个神经网络
network can compute complex nonlinear hypotheses.
是怎样计算非线性的假设函数
In the last video, we saw
在上一段视频中
how a neural network can
我们学习了
be used to compute the functions
怎样运用神经网络
x1 and x2 and the
来计算x1和x2的与运算
function x1 or x2 when
以及x1和x2的或运算
x1 and x2 are binary.
其中x1和x2都是二进制数
That is, when they take on values of 0, 1.
也就是说 它们的值只能为0或1
We can also have a
同时 我们也学习了
network to compute negation, that
怎样进行逻辑非运算
is to compute the function  "not x1".
也就是计算 "非x1"
Let me just write
我先写出这个神经网络中
down the ways associated with this network.
相连接的各权值
We have only one input feature, x1
这里我们只有一个输入量x1
in this case and the
在这里我们也加上了
bias unit plus 1 and
表示偏差的单位元 +1
if I associate this with
如果我将输入单元和两个权数相连
the weights +10 and
也就是+10和-20
-20 then my hypotheses is computing this.
则可用以下假设方程来计算
H of x equals sigmoid of
h(x)=g(10-20x1)
10 minus 20 times x1
其中g是一个S型函数
so when x1 is
那么
equal to 0, my
当x1等于0时
hypothesis will be computing
计算出假设函数
g of 10 minus
g(10-20*0)
20 times 0 which is just 10.
也就是g(10)
And so that's approximately
这个值近似的等于1
1, and when is x is
而当x等于1时
equal to 1 this will
计算出的假设函数则变成
be g of  -10, which
g(-10)
is therefore approximately equal to 0.
也就是约等于0
And if you look at what
如果你观察这两个值
these values are, that's essentially
你会发现这实际上计算的
the "not x1" function.
就是“非x1”函数
So to include negations, the
所以要计算逻辑非运算
general idea is to put
总体思路是
a large negative weight in front
在你希望取非运算的变量前面
of the variable you want to negate.
放上一个绝对值大的负数作为权值
So if it's -20, multiplied by
因此 如果放一个-20
x1 and, you know, that's the general
那么和x1相乘
idea of how you end
很显然 最终的结果
up negating x1.
就得到了对x1进行非运算的效果
And so, in an example that
另外 我再给出一个例子
I hope you will figure out
计算这样一个函数
yourself, if you want
(非x1)与(非x2)
to compute a function like this:
我希望大家思考一下
"not x1 and not x2"
自己动手算一算
you know, while part of that would
你大概应该知道
probably be putting large negative
至少应该在x1和x2前面
weights in front of x1
放一个绝对值比较大的负数作为权值
and x2, but it should
不过
be feasible to get a
还有一种可行的方法
neural network with just
是建立一个神经网络来计算
one output unit to compute this as well.
用只有一个输出单元的神经网络
All right?
没问题吧？
So, this large fill
因此
function "not x1 and not
这个看起来很长的逻辑函数
x2" is going to
“(非x1)与(非x2)”的值
be equal to 1
将等于1
if, and only if, x1
当且仅当
equals x2 equals zero, right?
x1等于x2等于0
So this is a logical function, this
所以 这是个逻辑函数
is not x1, that means x1 must be zero and not x2.
这里是非x1 也就是说x1必为0
That means x2 must be equal to zero as well.
然后是非x2 这表示x2也必为0
So this logical function is
因此这个逻辑函数等于1
equal to 1 if, and only
当且仅当
if, both x1 and x2 are equal to zero.
x1和x2的值都为0时成立
And hopefully, you should be
现在你应该也清楚了
able to figure out how to make a
怎样建立一个小规模的神经网络
small neural network to compute
来计算
this logical function as well.
这个逻辑函数的值
Now, taking the three pieces
把以上我们介绍的
that we have put together, the
这三个部分内容放在一起
network for computing x1 and
"x1与x2"与运算的网络
x2 and the network for
以及计算
computing not x1 and
"(非x1)与(非x2)"的网络
not x2 and one last
还有最后一个是
network for computing x1 or
"x1或x2"的或运算网络
x2, we should be
把这三个网络放在一起
able to put these three pieces together
我们就应该能计算
to compute this x1, XNOR
"x1 XNOR x2"
x2 function.
也就是同或门运算
And just to remind you, if
提醒一下
this was x1, x2, this
如果这是x1 x2
function that we want to
那么我们想要计算的这个函数
compute would have negative examples
在这里和这里是负样本
here and here and we'd
而在这里和这里
have positive examples there and there.
函数有正样本值
And so clearly this, you know, we'll
那么很显然
need a nonlinear decision boundary
为了分隔开正样本和负样本
in order to separate the positive and negative examples.
我们需要一个非线性的判别边界
Let's draw the network.
这里我们用以下这个网络来解决
I'm going to take my input
取输入单元
plus 1, x1, x2, and create
+1 x1和x2
my first hidden unit here.
建立第一个隐藏层单元
I'm going to call this a(2)1
我们称其为a(2)1
because that's my first hidden unit.
因为它是第一个隐藏单元
And I'm going to copy
接下来我要从红色的网络
the weights over from the Red
也就是"x1与x2"这个网络
Network, x1 and x2 networks.
复制出权值
So now minus 30, 20, 20.
也就是-30 20 20
Next, let me create
接下来
a second hidden unit, which
我再建立第二个隐藏单元
I'm going to call a(2)2 that
我们称之为a(2)2
is the second hidden unit of layer two.
它是第二层的第二个隐藏单元
And I'm going to copy over the
然后再从中间的青色网络中
Cyan Network in the
复制出权值
middle, so I'm going
这样我们就有了
to have the weights 10, minus 20,
10 -20 -20
minus 20.
这样三个权值
And so, let's pull some of the truth table values.
因此 我们来看一下真值表中的值
For the Red Network, we know
对于红色的这个网络
that was computing the x1 and x2.
我们知道是x1和x2的与运算
And so this is
所以
going to be approximately 0, 0,
这里的值大概等于0 0 0 1
0, 1, depending on the values of x1 and x2.
这取决于x1和x2的具体取值
And for a (2)2, that's the Cyan Network.
对于a (2)2 也就是青色的网络
Well that we know the function not x1
我们知道这是“(非x1)与(非x2)”的运算
and not x2 then outputs 1,
那么对于x1和x2的四种取值
0, 0, 0 for the
其结果将为
4 values of x1 and x2.
1 0 0 0
Finally, I'm going to
最后
create my output note, my
建立输出节点
output unit that is a(3)1.
也就是输出单元 a(3)1
This is one more output h
这也是等于输出值h(x)
of x and I'm
然后
going to copy over the OR
复制一个或运算网络
Network for that and I'm going to
同时
need a plus one bias unit here.
我需要一个+1作为偏差单元
So, draw that in and I'm
将其添加进来
going to copy over the weights from the Green Networks.
然后从绿色的网络中复制出所有的权值
So, it's minus 10, 20, 20
也就是-10 20 20
and we know earlier that this computes the OR function.
我们之前已经知道这是一个或运算函数
So, let's go on the truth table entries.
那么我们继续看真值表的值
For the first entry is 0
第一行的值是0和1的或运算
or 1, which is gonna be
其结果为1
1 then next 0 or
然后是0和0的或运算
0, which is 0,
其结果为0
0, or 0, which is 0,
0和0的或运算 结果还是0
1 or 0 and that all
1和0的或运算
is to 1 and thus, h
其结果为1
of x is equal to 1
因此 h(x)的值等于1
when either both x1 and
当x1和x2都为0
x2 are 0 or when x1 and
或者x1和x2都为1的时候成立
x2 are both 1. And
具体来说
concretely, h of x
在这两种情况时
outputs 1 exactly at these
h(x)输出1
two locations and it outputs
在另两种情况时
0 otherwise and thus,
h(x)输出0
with this neural network, which
那么对于这样一个神经网络
has an input layer, one
有一个输入层
hidden layer and one output
一个隐藏层
layer, we end up
和一个输出层
with a nonlinear decision boundary that
我们最终得到了
computes this XNOR function.
计算XNOR函数的非线性判别边界
And the more general intuition is
更一般的理解是
that in the input
在输入层中
layer, we just had our raw
我们只有原始输入值
inputs then we had
然后我们建立了一个隐藏层
a hidden layer, which computed some
用来计算稍微复杂一些的
slightly more complex functions of
输入量的函数
the inputs that is shown
如图所示
here, these are slightly more
这些都是稍微复杂一些的函数
complex functions, and then by
然后
adding yet another layer, we end
通过添加另一个层
up with an even more complex nonlinear function.
我们得到了一个更复杂一点的函数
And this is the sort of
这就是关于
intuition about why Neural
神经网络可以计算较复杂函数
Networks can compute pretty complicated
的某种直观解释
functions that when you
我们知道
have multiple layers, you have, you know,
当层数很多的时候
relatively simple function of
你有一个相对简单的输入量的函数
the inputs, and the second layer,
作为第二层
but the third layer can build
而第三层可以建立在此基础上
on that to compute even more
来计算更加复杂一些的函数
complex functions and then
然后再下一层
the layer after that can compute even more complex functions.
又可以计算再复杂一些的函数
To wrap up this video, I
在这段视频的最后
want to show you a fun example of
我想给大家展示一个有趣的例子
an application of a neural
这是一个神经网络
network that captures this intuition
通过运用更深的层数
of the deeper layers computing more complex features.
来计算更加复杂函数的例子
I want to show you
我将要展示的这段视频
a video that I got from
来源于我的一个好朋友
a good friend of mine, Yon Khun.
阳乐昆(Yann LeCun)
Yon is a professor at
Yann是一名教授
New York University, at NYU,
供职于纽约大学
and he was one of
他也是神经网络研究
the early pioneers of neural
早期的奠基者之一
network research and sort
也是这一领域的大牛
of a legend in the field
他的很多理论和想法
now and his ideas are
现在都已经被应用于
used in all sorts of products
各种各样的产品和应用中
and applications throughout the world now.
遍布于全世界
So, I want to show you
所以我想向大家展示一段
a video from some of his
他早期工作中的视频
early work in which he
这段视频中
was using a neural network
他使用神经网络的算法
to recognize handwriting - to do handwritten digit recognition.
进行手写数字的辨识
You might remember early in this
你也许记得
class, at the start of this
在这门课刚开始的时候
class, I said that one of
我说过
early successes of neural networks
关于神经网络的一个早期成就
was trying to use it
就是应用神经网络
to read zip codes, to help
读取邮政编码
us, you know, send mail along. So, to read postal codes.
以帮助我们进行邮递
So, this is one of the attempts.
那么这便是其中一种尝试
So, this is one of the
这就是为了解决这个问题
algorithms used to try to address that problem.
而尝试采用的一种算法
In the video I'll show you
在视频中
this area here is the
这个区域
input area that shows a
是输入区域
handwritten character shown to the
表示的是手写字符
network. This column here
它们将被传递给神经网络
shows a visualization of
这一列数字表示
the features computed by so that the
通过该网络第一个隐藏层运算后
first hidden layer of the
特征量的可视化结果
network and so the first
因此通过第一个隐藏层
hidden layer, you know, this visualization shows
可视化结果显示的是
different features, different edges and lines and so on detected.
探测出的不同特征 不同边缘和边线
This is a visualization of the next hidden layer.
这是下一个隐藏层的可视化结果
It's kind of harder to see
似乎很难看出
how to understand deeper hidden
怎样理解更深的隐藏层
layers and that's the visualization
以及下一个隐藏层
of what the next hidden layer is computing.
计算的可视化结果
You probably have a hard time
可能你如果要想看出到底在进行怎样的运算
seeing what's going on, you know,
还是比较困难的
much beyond the first hidden layer,
最终远远超出了第一个隐藏层的效果
but then finally, all of
但不管怎样
these learned features get
最终这些学习后的特征量
fed to the output layer
将被送到最后一层 也就是输出层
and shown over here is
并且在最后作为结果
the final answers, the final
显示出来
predictive value for what
最终预测到的结果
handwritten digit the neural network things that is being shown.
就是这个神经网络辨识出的手写数字的值
So, let's take a look at the video.
下面我们来观看这段视频
So, I hope
我希望你
you enjoyed the video and that
喜欢这段视频
this hopefully gave you some
也希望这段视频能给你一些直观的感受
intuition about the sorts
关于神经网络可以学习的
of pretty complicated functions neural
较为复杂一些的函数
networks can learn in which
在这个过程中
it takes this input this image,
它使用的输入是不同的图像
just takes this input the
或者说
raw pixels and the first
就是一些原始的像素点
end of the layer computes some set
第一层计算出一些特征
of features, the next end
然后下一层再计算出
of the layer computes even more complex
一些稍复杂的特征
features and even more complex features
然后是更复杂的特征
and these features can then be
然后这些特征
used by essentially the final
实际上被最终传递给
layer of logistic regression classifiers
最后一层逻辑回归分类器上
to make accurate predictions about what
使其准确地预测出
are the numbers that the network sees.
神经网络“看”到的数字